Benny Hassan, Full Stack Developer

Bennyh960@gmail.com

Phone: 052-4874600





Chemical Engineer (B.sc) in the past and Full Stack developer in the present. Motivated with high learning abilities, self-taught, and very friendly. Skilled in Front-End and Back-End technologies. Experience in process design, development, and project management.

Coding Projects

2022 – Backend Developer, practical internship at Dealigence (Bootstrapped startup - 3 months)

- ❖ Developing "Connection Assessment" API, which aims to evaluate connections strength between entities stored in DB using **Postgres (SQL)**.
- Design the required tables and their relationships (one-to-many, many-to-many, polymorphic association).
- Retrieve data using scrapers, Parse it and load it into the database (NodeJS, Puppeteer, Scrape-it, Sequelize ORM).
- ❖ Building complex queries focusing on efficiency (indexing, window function).

My Portfolio Including plenty of my coding projects (such as the Bootcamp final project "MeetBach" which includes plenty of features using MongoDB, React, Socket-io). (Git, Demo)

EDUCATION

Full Stack Developer Bootcamp - AppelSeeds (Mar. 2022- Sep. 2022)

- ❖ Intensive 6-months, 720 hours training program that encourages self-led.
- learning and group projects that simulate real-world development teams, including Git workflow.
- Learning and applying front-end skills such as **HTML**, **CSS**, **JavaScript**.
- React and back-end skills such as **Node.js** and **MongoDB** database.

B.Sc in Chemical Engineering, SCE Ashdod (2011-2015)

Graduated with excellence (GPA 93).

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Process Engineer, Intel (2018-2021)

- ❖ Tool owner of production machines, responsible for tool performance, data, writing work plans, troubleshooting, and Validation.
- Project management to improve Tool availability and quality performance.

Process Engineer, Merck (2015-2018)

- Design and develop technological production processes, problem-solving, and improving product quality.
- Pilots operation, process improvement, and writing work plans.

Languages: Hebrew native speaker **English** Highly proficient

Skills: Analytical thinking, Curious, Interpersonal communication, Motivated, self-taught ...